<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
	<channel>
		<title>ComplexCity Lab's Blog</title>
		<link>http://complexcity.org/blog/</link>
		<description>A Comprehensive Blog on Smart and Social City</description>
	

		<item>
			<title>What is a city?</title>
			<link>http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/06/23/.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/06/23/.html</guid>
			<pubDate>2014-06-23T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;The outstanding work of &lt;em&gt;The Spirit of Cities&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] by Bell and de-Shalit gives a very interesting point of view at how some cities are unique for their citizens. As a matter of fact more and more Chinese citizens feel detached from their cities. They find it difficult to recognize their city identity whereas identity might be a key factor to integrate millions of people in a short time to new urban area without them feeling they do not belong here or that they live just-another-lambda city.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
	
	

		<item>
			<title>Tianzifang: Community or Tourism?</title>
			<link>http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/06/16/.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/06/16/.html</guid>
			<pubDate>2014-06-16T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;Tianzifang (田子坊) is an arts and crafts enclave that has developed from a renovated residential area in Shanghai, China. It is known for small craft stores, coffee shops, art studios and narrow alleys. “Despite all the businesses selling trendy foreign goods, the area does not have the look of having been overly beautified - electricity cables are still strung overhead, and air conditioning units are obvious on the outside of the buildings. The district is distinctly different from Xintiandi, another Shikumen redevelopment in the vicinity to the north, in that it has managed to preserve its residential feel, adding to its appeal.”1 However, to preserve this “residential feel”, conflicts among local residents, developers, shop owners, and tourists are getting increasingly intensive, which brought us an inevitable question: should we pay more attention to a healthy-growing community or an economic-beneficial tourism?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conflicts Between Stakeholders’ Interests Compared with large-scale redevelopment and relocation projects in other parts of Shanghai, it is understandable that local residents are easier to feel injustice and despair of the fact that, after the renovation of Tianzifang, there is barely chance for them to obtain large amounts of relocation compensation like others to move to new-built apartments. Unlike the situation in Japan, where inhabitants tend to put preservation of culture heritage above their own interests, Chinese residents, especially those who live in old communities with low-income, care about nothing as important as their own benefits. In France or other western countries, inhabitants are delighted to see renovation of their communities while they can still keep their everyday life there. In short, regeneration of Tianzifang deprives the expectation/opportunities of inhabitants for relocation and the following economic profits. To vent this discontent, they call the police to complain about the noise or other infringements caused by the tourists, hang posters or slogans in Tianzifang. Another factor needs to be taken into account is the conflict of different lifestyles. A relatively large proportion of senior citizens are living in Tianzifang, and they prefer to stay rather than move to new places. Many of them stick to a routine lifestyle, i.e., sleep around 8 pm and wake up around 4 am. Nevertheless, young tourists enjoy a modern nightlife, which usually starts around 9 pm and ends around 3 am. In other words, the party time for young generations overlaps the rest time for elderly residents. This conflict is not just reflected in Tianzifang, but in other places where recreation facilities (e.g. bars, cafe) are mixed with residential area, such as Yongkang Rd., etc. The pouring tourists enjoy the bustling shops, trendy art studios, and leisure residential feel most. Tianzifang provides an invaluable opportunity for them to engage multiple activities, such as relaxing, shopping, people-watching, more importantly, to experience authentic Shanghai life and fully contact with Linong culture. Besides, all the foreign goods, exotic restaurants, cafe, and bars well represent the openness of Shanghai, and the city’s willing to embrace people all around the world. It is strongly appreciated by both Chinese and international visitors. The government and developers (Administrative Committee of Taikanglu Art Street, Shikumen Owners Management Committee (NGO), and artists) emphasize on how to effectively avoid the problems of Xintiandi development mode, which is often criticized as “fake” by tourists, for its lack of residential atmosphere caused by relocation of original communities. From Tianzifang renovation project, we can see developers’ effort to uplift local economy while create a mixed-function community and inclusive society, and it is undoubtedly praisable. Moreover, this innovative mode is more appealing to tourists who look forward to experiencing the “good old Shanghai life”. Meanwhile, it preserves the traditional Shikumen buildings and Shanghai’s Linong (里弄) culture. However, to some extent, it excludes some residents’ expectations for achieving certain benefits from a typical gentrification process, such as a large-scale redevelopment project. Posters hung at Tianzifang by the inhabitants (with pictures) 坚决反对民宿，我们要活命、要生存 We are firmly against boarding house (bed and breakfast), that we need to live and survive. 坚决禁止噪声扰民，还我一个安静安全的环境 We are firmly against noise nuisance. Give me back my quiet and safe environment! 强烈要求政府实施晚10时商家停止营业 We strongly demand that the government enforce all shops close business at 10pm.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Answer: Arts Rejuvenation + E-tourism 1. Arts Rejuvenation Tianzifang was named after a famous painter in China’s foundational texts of Daoism “Zhuangzi”, Chapter 21 “Tianzifang”2 (See the legend below). At the beginning, the renovation of Tianzifang was initiated by a group of famous artists who moved into some simply renovated factory space as their art studios with the intention to rejuvenate the dilapidated community and to make the place better known. Then, an expansion into the residential area progressed beyond factory boundaries, and spaces for creative industry gradually grew into smaller alleys. “With the expansion, the artistic atmosphere infiltrated into the Shikumen residential area and changed pure residential characters. The artists and designers settled renovated old houses by themselves and updated the function of the buildings. Interior spaces have been converted into unique spaces for creativity industry, and newly added signs and door fittings on façade interplay with old building structures underlain, and narrow old allays are visually animated.”3 (Hiroyuki Shinohara) However, the continuing expansion of non-residential use were extended to more commercial ones such as coffee shops, bars, restaurants, retails. On the one hand, it brought considerable economic benefits by attracting thousands of tourists per day; on the other hand, it deteriorated the conflicts between inhabitants and visitors, and went far against its intention as a creative industry accumulated district of Shanghai. American cities are also actively engaging arts into community revival. For instance, through cultural organization and engagement-based arts programming, “Big Car” Project brings together people of all backgrounds in local Indiana communities to inspire creativity and activate public spaces. It collaborates with local residents and stakeholders by forming partnerships in order to build social capital and encourage civically engaged communities. Big Car utilizes the unique “social practice art,” i.e., individuals that may not necessarily define themselves as artists become directly involved in the process of art, building connections and empathy among participants4.&lt;br /&gt;According to the inspiring practice of “Big Car” Project and the retrospection of the growing history of Tianzifang, it may be more suitable for the future sustainable development of the area to encourage in-depth public participation into art activities, pursue creative solutions to attract and gather artists, and utilize art and artists to engage residents in creative dialogue, instead of further turning the area into a tourism-oriented commercial street. It is time to bridge the gap between art institutions and residents, in a word, not just “bring art to people”, but also “bring people to art”. 2. E-tourism As Secretary Fleur Pellerin pointed out, “the development of digital technology and mobility constitutes a major change in the tourist experience.”5, ComplexCity Lab is willing to make Tianzifang a successful sample in terms of “e-tourism” by taking full advantage of the available public data and serving for all participants. We are capable of managing data to optimize the attractiveness of Tianzifang and making better use of its “cultural and creative capital”. The methodology is, implementing a community-wide solution (such as Tianzifang) and use it as a standard benchmark for further promotion. Specific applicable solutions include, from the experience applied in Paris, recycling the heat generated by shops, restaurants, and art studios as a byproduct for heating and supplying electricity for all residential buildings. With the extensive use of smart phone, all shops will receive text messages to remind them keep voice down after 10 pm. With the help of geographic-tracking apps, when tourists approach residential area, they will get text messages to remind them of the fact that people are living there, thus, they may need to change their behavior. Building digital map of Tianzifang with the option of picking up purchases at the tourists’ preference stores or studios, to best avoid the trespass of residential area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Appendix Legend of “Tianzifang”: Yuan King of Song (531–517 BC) asked for paintings, so all the painters arrived in the palace. They stood aside after kowtowed and made their bow. After, they wet their painting brush and prepared the ink. However, half of them were laymen. There was one painter arrived late. He looked leisurely, and didn’t follow the royal rite to walk fast. He politely bowed but didn’t stand up, instead, he returned home immediately. The King sent the herald to check up on him, and found that he took off his coat, sat down with his legs crossed, lifted his sleeves, and was holding his painting brush. “Yes, he is the true great painter” said the King. (宋元君将画图，众史皆至，受揖而立，舐笔和墨，在外者半。有一史后至者，譠譠然不趋，受揖不立，因之舍。公使人视之，则解衣盘礴，裸袖握管。君曰：“可矣，是真画者也。” )&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bibliography&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Tianzifang&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Zhuangzi_(book)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Hiroyuki Shinohara (Architect/Lecturer), “Mutation of Tianzifang, Taikang Road, Shanghai”, The 4th Conference of the International Forum on Urbanism, 2009&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Jenna Chilingerian (CEOs for Cities), “Engagement Through Arts”, 2013&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Fleur Pellerin (French Secretary of State for Foreign Trade, Tourism Promotion and French overseas), “France must become the world standard for e-tourism”, 2014&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
		</item>
	
	

		<item>
			<title>Small or medium size cities? Or big cities? A hukou-based analysis</title>
			<link>http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/06/09/.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/06/09/.html</guid>
			<pubDate>2014-06-09T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;According to comprehensive and publicly available statistical data, the cost of “urbanizing” each person is approximately 20,000 yuan in a small city, and 100,000 yuan in a large one. With Kam Wing Chan’s calculation of the overall cost of urbanizing the entire floating population and its fiscal impact, offering urban hukou to 20 million people per year (assuming that the migrant population will reach 300 million by 2030) in big cities would cost 50 billion yuan, aka 0.1 % of China’s GDP, a figure within the country’s affordability. It brings out the position we stand for, since big cities are capable to afford the cost of urbanizing the floating population, the small or middle ones should be better as the cost of “per-capita urbanization” is lower. Is it sustainable to continue the policy and investment preference to big cities, or should we reconsider the role of small or medium size cities in China’s urbanization?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;习近平强调，推进人的城镇化重要的环节在户籍制度，加快户籍制度改革，是涉及亿万农业转移人口的一项重大举措。总的政策要求是全面放开建制镇和小城市落户限制，有序放开中等城市落户限制，合理确定大城市落户条件，严格控制特大城市人口规模，促进有能力在城镇稳定就业和生活的常住人口有序实现市民化，稳步推进城镇基本公共服务常住人口全覆盖。户籍制度改革是一项复杂的系统工程，既要统筹考虑，又要因地制宜、区别对待。要坚持积极稳妥、规范有序，充分考虑能力和可能，优先解决存量，有序引导增量。要尊重城乡居民自主定居意愿，合理引导农业转移人口落户城镇的预期和选择。要促进大中小城市和小城镇合理布局、功能互补，搞好基本公共服务，还要维护好农民的土地承包经营权、宅基地使用权、集体收益分配权。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;根据教育部网站11日发布的一项文件，各地区、各有关部门要积极采取措施，促进就业公平。省会及以下城市用人单位招聘应届毕业生不得将户籍作为限制性条件。用人单位招聘不得设置民族、种族、性别、宗教信仰等歧视性条件，不得将院校作为限制性条件。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;文件要求，各地区、各有关部门要消除高校毕业生在不同地区、不同类型单位之间流动就业的制度性障碍。省会及以下城市要放开对吸收高校毕业生落户的限制，简化有关手续，应届毕业生凭《普通高等学校毕业证书》、《全国普通高等学校毕业生就业报到证》、与用人单位签订的《就业协议书》或劳动（聘用）合同办理落户手续；非应届毕业生凭与用人单位签订的劳动（聘用）合同和《普通高等学校毕业证书》办理落户手续。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;文件强调，各地区、各有关部门要严厉打击非法中介和虚假招聘，依法纠正性别、民族等就业歧视现象。加大对企业用工行为的监督检查力度，对企业招用高校毕业生不签订劳动合同、不按时足额缴纳社会保险费、不按时支付工资等违法行为，及时予以查处，切实维护高校毕业生的合法权益。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;根据文件要求，高校毕业生到小型微型企业就业、自主创业的，其档案可由当地市、县一级的公共就业人才服务机构免费保管。办理高校毕业生档案转递手续，转正定级表、调整改派手续不再作为接收审核档案的必备材料。&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In recent years, the State Council has proposed implementing a policy encouraging migrant workers to settle down in small and medium cities, but not in the largest 40 cities. Some commentators have high hopes for this policy, claiming that it is an urbanisation path with “Chinese characteristics,” which can help the country avoid the “big city disease” by channeling migrants to small and medium cities. Dr. Chan argues that it is a gross misunderstanding and provides her analysis as the reality of China’s investment is still tilted toward major cities, and large cities develop more quickly. Migrant workers have for the most part not followed policy to small cities but have moved to the large cities because of jobs. With the current local government revenue system dominated by land sales revenues, local governments of small cities do not have the means to develop the cities because the land there cannot be sold at a good price. However, it is not totally impossible to attract migrant workers to middle or small cities. Deng Xiaoping reiterated that “some areas must get rich before others”, and asserted that the wealth from coastal regions will eventually be transferred to aid economic construction inland. The theory, however, faced numerous challenges when put into practice, as provincial governments moved to protect their own interests. In spite of the difficult situation to ask provincial governments “sacrifice” part of their interests, the society won’t make a progress if everyone remain a selfish attitude and ignore other cities welfare. Without effective solutions to de migrants to small or medium size cities, big cities will have to take the burden of accepting pouring migrants no matter they like it or not, and eventually, hurt every part’s interests. Considering what migrants need, the reason they go to big cities mainly include big cities have the wherewithal and talents to be the most efficient and most productive in many respects. However, without convenient access to good or advanced public service(due to lack of legitimate Hukou), the city can mean nothing to migrant workers, and this, has been proved by numerous investigations of their feelings to big cities they live and work. Therefore, instead of working hard on big cities, why don’t we&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bibliography 1. President Xi’s&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;http://news.ifeng.com/a/20140606/40627314_0.shtml 2. 教育部文件 http://news.ifeng.com/a/20140611/40694378_0.shtml&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
	
	

		<item>
			<title></title>
			<link>http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/06/02/.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/06/02/.html</guid>
			<pubDate>2014-06-02T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
			<description></description>
		</item>
	
	

		<item>
			<title>Some thoughts during the Youth Planners&#39; Innovation Forum at Tongji University</title>
			<link>http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/05/26/.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/05/26/.html</guid>
			<pubDate>2014-05-26T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;It is important to differ migrant workers and migrants when conducting research on public policy for coordinating rural and urban development. Migrant workers pursue the most interest for working in a city while migrants pursue to be involved in urban life and social inclusion. Is it necessary to provide low-rent housing for migrant workers? They don’t seek to live in cities, but only to make as much profits as they can. To those who really intend to be members of urban society, we should not just offer them urban identity such as urban hukou, but also make them feel involved by organizing community participation, etc.. Li Zhigang (Sun Yat-sen University)’s research shows that, valuing the role of Middle class when proposing planning mechanism for mix-living model may be beneficial for .&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another opinion being discussed during the forum provides a possible solution for easing the burden of social inclusion in big cities is called In-situ Urbanization.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By the mid-1980s, attitudes toward urbanization began to shift, with cities coming to be viewed as “growth poles” and the “city as leading the country.” Some Chinese researchers argued that “growth poles should be scattered through the country, each sending waves of economic growth in its hinterland” (Fan 1997: 630). In order to accelerate industrialization and meet the needs of construction and other services, cities had to absorb more migrants. Moreover, the small towns that had become important foci for industrial development grew to become substantial urban centers with concentrations of industry and were reclassified as cities, a process known as in situ urbanization. To prevent the further marginalization of rural area, it is vital to enhance the attraction of rural area to keep the farmers/potential migrant workers instead of leave all the burdens of urban-rural integration to big cities. In-situ urbanization can promote infrastructure and social welfare development in rural areas, attract more investment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Construction of “shuttle” transportation system among universities in Shanghai. The agglomeration of intelligence boost local development. However, from Shanghai University to Tongji University, students usually need to take 3 different lines on subway, which the opportunity of face-to-face communication of students from different university. In the long run, it may… My suggestion is building a transportation system connects all the universities in Shanghai without stop at other places, which is 100% students/ faculties oriented to promote the idea exchgange of well-educated people.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
		</item>
	
	

		<item>
			<title>Hukou system for college graduates</title>
			<link>http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/05/19/hukou-system-for-college-graduates.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://complexcity.org/blog//2014/05/19/hukou-system-for-college-graduates.html</guid>
			<pubDate>2014-05-19T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;In China, each person has a registration (hukou) in either a rural area or an urban area, and cannot change the hukou without the permission of the receiving jurisdiction. David Dollar, World Bank Country, explains “Hukou system kept rural-urban migration below what it otherwise would have been, and contributed to the development of one of the largest rural-urban income divides in the world.” In short, it is much like a green card or “internal passport” that provides its bearer access to public service, such as health care, education, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To achieve the “Chinese dream”, some researchers point that it is important to give all migrants an urban hukou within the next 15 years. We believe the relaxation of the hukou system should benefit for all, but also considering it can only be done with several steps and granting a hukou to college graduates as a major step. In western world, many countries and businesses foresee the potential of intellectuals as catalyst for local economic boom, and advocate relevant policies to attract college graduates, regardless of their origin. As President Obama emphasized this in his State of Union address:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let’s stop expelling talented, responsible young people who could be staffing our research labs or starting a new business, who could be further enriching this nation.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fairly speaking, China’s policy makers already see the importance of enhancing the mobility of highly educated people, and are taking some actions as offering land or taxes preferential policy. However, in big cities, the hukou system still repulses graduates who come from other localities. Kam Wing Chan, professor of geography at University of Washington, former consultant of urbanization and urban migration projects for the United Nations and the World Bank, writes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Each year, the numbers of migrant graduates who gain a local hukou in large cities like Shanghai and Beijing is very small, ranging from a few hundred to perhaps one or two thousand out of hundreds of thousands of college-educated migrants in each city.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, it is not convenient for graduates transferring their hukous among Chinese cities, especially when considering the ever-growing trend of frequent migration for work of young people. Today China’s higher education system provides services including assisting students transferring their hukou during graduation period. However, if a student does not obtain a job offer when he graduates, his/her hukou will be moved to local College Graduates Employment Guidance Center (高校毕业生就业指导中心) automatically. Only after he/she gets a job, his/her hukou can be transferred to the workplace. If a student intends to go abroad and move the hukou back to his/her hometown, there will be a complicated process to go through. Some local authorities ask college graduates to prove their “unmarried” status as a prerequisite to move their hukou back under the reason of “Children join their parents” (外地子女投靠父母), which requires students to go back to the cities where they studied for the proof of their marital status. It is an expensive and time-consuming process since a large part of students move to other cities far away after graduation. The regulation also changes numerous students who left home for study to a “floating population” (外来人口) and deprives them of their full rights to access public services before they successfully move their hukou back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Again, the foreseeable solution for this issue could be the relaxation of the hukou system for college graduates, especially gradually abolishing the requirement for their “unmarried” status. It may also be helpful to build an on-line database about personal residential information for further verification instead of demanding students to commute among different cities in person for the hukou-transferring paperwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/hukou_system&quot;&gt;Hukou system, wikipedia&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Dollar, David. “Poverty, inequality and social disparities during China’s economic reform” &lt;a href=&quot;http://econ.worldbank.org/external/default/main?pagePK=64165259&amp;theSitePK=477872&amp;piPK=64165421&amp;menuPK=64166093&amp;entityID=000016406_20070613095018&quot; title=&quot;paper on The World Bank&quot;&gt;The World Bank&lt;/a&gt;. June 6, 2007.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;Chan, Kam Wing. “A road map for reforming China’s hukou system”. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chinadialogue.net/article/show/single/en/6432-A-road-map-for-reforming-China-s-hukou-system&quot; title=&quot;article on ChinaDialogue.net&quot;&gt;ChinaDialogue.net&lt;/a&gt;. October 22, 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;“新政发力促进优秀人才来无锡就业创业”. &lt;a href=&quot;http://jsnews.jschina.com.cn/system/2014/04/29/020873979.shtml&quot; title=&quot;article on www.jschina.com.cn&quot;&gt;中国江苏网&lt;/a&gt;. April 29, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.npc.gov.cn/wxzl/gongbao/2000-12/10/content_5004332.htm&quot;&gt;《中华人民共和国户口登记条例》&lt;/a&gt; (Regulations on Household Registration of the People’s Republic of China)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
		</item>
	
	

		<item>
			<title>Identity of Chinese cities</title>
			<link>http://complexcity.org/blog//china/cities/2014/05/12/identity-of-chinese-cities.html</link>
			<guid isPermaLink="true">http://complexcity.org/blog//china/cities/2014/05/12/identity-of-chinese-cities.html</guid>
			<pubDate>2014-05-12T00:00:00+08:00</pubDate>
			<description>&lt;p&gt;The outstanding work of &lt;em&gt;The Spirit of Cities&lt;/em&gt; [&lt;a href=&quot;#1&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;] by Bell and de-Shalit gives a very interesting point of view at how some cities are unique for their citizens. As a matter of fact more and more Chinese citizens feel detached from their cities. They find it difficult to recognize their city identity whereas identity might be a key factor to integrate millions of people in a short time to new urban area without them feeling they do not belong here or that they live just-another-lambda city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Several obstacles stand in the way of Chinese planners we would like to emphasize: wealth gap, integration of migrant, worldwide disinterest for citizenship responsibility, city official planning expertise among the stronger ones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The authors argue that it is a key factor for promoting urban identity that the city does not have a huge gap between rich and poor or between ethnic and racial groups. Argument is that if people live separate lives and strongly dislike one another, they will find it difficult to share a common interest. Given the huge class/social gap in Chinese cities (according to the numerous researches published on World Bank report [&lt;a href=&quot;#2&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;], Forbes [&lt;a href=&quot;#3&quot;&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;], NY Times [&lt;a href=&quot;#4&quot;&gt;4&lt;/a&gt;], NBC News [&lt;a href=&quot;#5&quot;&gt;5&lt;/a&gt;], it will be very hard for Chinese cities to promote urban identities effectively without proper integration of different class of population.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gap is especially true when speaking about the severe living status of migrant workers. In recent decades, Chinese migrant workers came to cities for jobs taking benefit of the construction boom but as Isabel Hilton stated for ChinaDialogue [&lt;a href=&quot;#6&quot;&gt;6&lt;/a&gt;]:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With no right of abode they are locked into the status of a disadvantaged underclass, allowed to work in cities but not to enjoy the right of residence that would give them and their families access to health care or public education. .&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consequently, how do we expect them to contribute to create a strong urban identity while they are struggling to meet the basic needs of life? According to the research by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chinadialogue.net/&quot;&gt;ChinaDialogue&lt;/a&gt;, prejudice against migrant workers plagues urban society. Marginalization has left many migrants disenchanted. A 52-year-old migrant worker in Beijing expressed trenchantly what people think [&lt;a href=&quot;#7&quot;&gt;7&lt;/a&gt;]:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;No matter how long we live and work here, Beijing could never be our home&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The deterioration of urban identity is closely related to issues of social justice since it is difficult for the marginalized to feel they belong somewhere. But if such a climate makes it difficult for a city identity to emerge, contribute to the emergence through integration of migrant culture into design, planning, and city life is also a solution to give citizens something they can all relate to regardless of their income levels, cultures, age, etc. City might be the good place to embody this craver for harmony [&lt;a href=&quot;#8&quot;&gt;8&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another factor mentioned by Bell and de-Shalit is that the residents have a strong motivation to struggle to keep their identity when the urban identity is threatened by outside forces. Such as the people of Hong Kong fight to maintain their capitalist way of life as opposed to mainland China [&lt;a href=&quot;#9&quot;&gt;9&lt;/a&gt;]. Unfortunately, public participation and conceptions such as “fighting for the rights” are not deeply rooted in Chinese people’s minds [&lt;a href=&quot;#10&quot;&gt;10&lt;/a&gt;]. Many citizens don’t take fighting for the urban identity as their obligation. Instead, they see it more likely as a “government business/affair” even though regulation in China ask for citizens approval.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to &lt;em&gt;Urban and Rural Planning Law of the People’s Republic of China&lt;/em&gt;, Article 26:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before filing an urban or rural planning for examination and approval, the organ establishing it shall announce the draft of the planning and collect opinions from experts and the general public by way of argumentation, hearing or other. The draft shall be announced for at least 30 days.（《城乡规划法》第二十六条：城乡规划报送审批前，组织编制机关应当依法将城乡规划草案予以公告，并采取论证会、听证会或者其他方式征求专家和公众的意见。公告的时间不得少于三十日。）[&lt;a href=&quot;#11&quot;&gt;11&lt;/a&gt;].&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fact citizens do not feel involved in their city life is not specific to China. Here technology have a strong role to play here by making citizen experience their city present and future. Smart city and smart government are beginning to answer this need. It is our duty to design effective ways to stimulate people’s passion for public participation on reviving or promoting urban identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The book also points out that it is essential for cities to have great urban planners to enact transformative plans that help to realize a common public urban identity. Environment contributes most to urban identity since they provide a space to experiment and live in to both residents and tourists. However, urban planning in China became a &lt;em&gt;manufacturing process&lt;/em&gt; which creates numerous soulless and homogeneous cities. Local governments leave the planning jobs to design companies or schools, and most of them merely take it as an opportunity to make profits instead of an invaluable chance to revive urban identity. Therefore, urban planning in China often turns to drawing grand blueprints to meet local officials’ ideas.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What makes it worse is, since most officials are not well-trained with professional knowledge of planning or urban studies, many of their &lt;em&gt;visions&lt;/em&gt; are merely impacted by the image conveyed by the media of what &lt;em&gt;future cities&lt;/em&gt; should look like. As a result, we see massive imitation of used planning models in many Chinese cities [&lt;a href=&quot;#12&quot;&gt;12&lt;/a&gt;], especially in new-built areas, such as car-oriented big streets, oversized city halls, etc. But to be fair, China’s urbanization face a unique situation. Many cities are preparing themselves to welcome millions of people in the next 10 years or so and this situation is unique in the world. Therefore time is an issue and it is pretty hard to foresee what society needs will be. To keep or develop an identity based on history and culture might not be the top priority even if it guarantees social stability in the future to connect to the past and gives everyone a reason to be proud of living somewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;CEOs for Cities [&lt;a href=&quot;#13&quot;&gt;13&lt;/a&gt;] argues that:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unique characteristics of place may be the only truly defensible source of competitive advantage for regions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If Chinese cities are willing to achieve their ambitions and be highly competitive and attractive in the 21st century, it is essential to keep their own unique characteristics, engage people’s emotions and bring people a new whole experience about the city they live and work in by reviving urban identity. After all, the only way to mark the city in the trend of globalization is to effectively nourish and promote the particularity of city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bibliography&quot;&gt;Bibliography&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;1&#39; /&gt;Bell, Daniel A., and Avner De-Shalit. &lt;em&gt;The spirit of cities: Why the identity of a city matters in a global age&lt;/em&gt;. Princeton University Press, 2011. (see it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.goodreads.com/book/show/11452166-the-spirit-of-cities&quot; title=&quot;book on GoodReads&quot;&gt;GoodReads&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;2&#39; /&gt;Dollar, David. “Poverty, inequality and social disparities during China’s economic reform” &lt;a href=&quot;http://econ.worldbank.org/external/default/main?pagePK=64165259&amp;theSitePK=477872&amp;piPK=64165421&amp;menuPK=64166093&amp;entityID=000016406_20070613095018&quot; title=&quot;paper on The World Bank&quot;&gt;The World Bank&lt;/a&gt;. June 6, 2007.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;3&#39; /&gt;Rapoza, Kenneth. “The China Miracle: A Rising Wealth Gap”. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.forbes.com/sites/kenrapoza/2013/01/20/the-china-miracle-a-rising-wealth-gap/&quot; title=&quot;article on Forbes&quot;&gt;Forbes&lt;/a&gt;. January 20, 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;4&#39; /&gt;Wong, Edward. “Survey in China Shows a Wide Gap in Income”. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nytimes.com/2013/07/20/world/asia/survey-in-china-shows-wide-income-gap.html&quot; title=&quot;article on The New York Times&quot;&gt;The New York Times&lt;/a&gt;. July 19, 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;5&#39; /&gt;Schoen, John W. “China’s wealth gap strains social fabric”. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nbcnews.com/id/39546204/ns/business-world_business/t/chinas-wealth-gap-strains-social-fabric/&quot; title=&quot;article on NBC News&quot;&gt;NBC News&lt;/a&gt;. October 20, 2010.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;6&#39; /&gt;Hilton, Isabel. “China’s Urban Dilemma”. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chinadialogue.net/article/show/single/en/6459-China-s-urban-dilemma&quot; title=&quot;article on ChinaDialogue.net&quot;&gt;ChinaDialogue.net&lt;/a&gt;. November 11, 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;7&#39; /&gt;Lin, Luna. “Chinese migrants struggle to find urban dream”. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chinadialogue.net/article/show/single/en/6426-Chinese-migrants-struggle-to-find-urban-dream&quot; title=&quot;article on ChinaDialogue.net&quot;&gt;ChinaDialogue.net&lt;/a&gt;. October 18, 2013.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;8&#39; /&gt;Barber, Benjamin R. “If mayors ruled the world.” &lt;em&gt;Why cities can and should govern globally and how they already do&lt;/em&gt;. Yale University Press, 2013. (see it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.fr/Mayors-Ruled-World-Barber-Benjamin-ebook/dp/B00FOR56YY/ref=sr_1_1?s=digital-text&amp;amp;ie=UTF8&amp;amp;qid=1401093542&amp;amp;sr=1-1&amp;amp;keywords=if+mayor+ruled+the+world&quot; title=&quot;book on Amazon&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;9&#39; /&gt;Lipin, Michael. “Honk Kong Anti-Mainlander Protest Highlights Frustration With Visitor Influx”. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.voanews.com/content/hong-kong-anti-mainlander-protest-highlights-frustration-with-visitor-influx/1862703.html&quot; title=&quot;article on Voice of America&quot;&gt;Voice of America&lt;/a&gt;.March 2, 2014.&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;10&#39; /&gt;Yi, Li. &lt;em&gt;Public Participation Issues in Preservation Planning: Practices of Chinese Historic District.&lt;/em&gt; (Masters Thesis). University of Pennsylvania, Philadelphia, PA, 2012. (see it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://repository.upenn.edu/hp_theses/193/&quot; title=&quot;paper on University of Pennsylvania ScholarlyCommons&quot;&gt;University of Pennsylvania ScholarlyCommons&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;11&#39; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://wenku.baidu.com/link?url=lxmciTjBn01dCViZ2jWXhSKzFWkcUUsLGctpNuRghDuum5l60HXEam22VvfjCgDfrqziFht6n27p87T_4ydtn6fSOqC1NjEqhHhYkWbnv-m&quot; title=&quot;《中华人民共和国城乡规划法》&quot;&gt;中华人民共和国城乡规划法&lt;/a&gt; (Urban and Rural Planning Law of the People’s Republic of China)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;12&#39; /&gt;Xu, Jiang and Anthony G.O. Yeh., “City Repositioning and Competitiveness Building in Regional Development: New Development Strategies in Guangzhou, China.” &lt;em&gt;International Journal of Urban and Regional Research&lt;/em&gt;, 29 (2005): 283–308. doi: 10.1111/j.1468-2427.2005.00585.x (see it on &lt;a href=&quot;http://onlinelibrary.wiley.com/doi/10.1111/j.1468-2427.2005.00585.x/abstract&quot; title=&quot;paper on Wiley Online Library&quot;&gt;Wiley Online Library&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;a name=&#39;13&#39; /&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ceosforcities.org/city-vitals&quot; title=&quot;CEOs for Cities&quot;&gt;CEOs for Cities&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;</description>
		</item>
	
	
	</channel>
</rss>
